Inventory of the George Haven Putnam papers, circa 1800-1931
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
George Haven Putnam papers
circa 1800-1931
1860-1931
Putnam, George Haven, 1844-1930.
04418
12 cubic feet (32 boxes)
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Biography of George Haven Putnam
George Haven Putnam was the son of publisher George Palmer Putnam, founder of G.P. Putnam & Co., which had offices in New York and London. He served during the Civil War with the 176th New York Volunteers from 1862-1865, rising to the rank of major. As a prisoner of war, he spent the winter of 1864-1865 in Libby and Danville prisons. Putnam joined his father's publishing house after the Civil War and became head of G.P. Putnam's Sons in 1872, a position he held until his death in 1930. He was an organizer of the American Copyright League in 1887 and was instrumental in the development of American copyright law.
Putnam was actively involved in the English-Speaking Union, the American Rights League, the Free Trade League, and support of the League of Nations. From 1926 until his death he devoted his efforts to creating an endowed chair in American history at the University of London. Putnam wrote several books and lectured widely on subjects including his Civil War experiences, Abraham Lincoln, copyright, censorship, publishing, free trade, American-British relations and Washington Irving.
Scope and Content
Collection includes correspondence with many writers, political leaders and other notables (1840-1931); texts and notes for speeches; articles and publications by Putnam; scrapbooks of personal and Putnam Co. memorabilia; and miscellaneous other materials.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by George Haven Putnam at the date of processing.
Additional Information
Finding aid available in repository.
Acquisition Information
The collection was received from Jessie Hale in 1972.
Access Terms
Putnam family.; Irving, Washington, 1783-1859.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; G.P. Putnam & Co.; G.P. Putnam's Sons.; Free Trade League.; English-Speaking Union of the United States.; League of Nations.; American Rights League.; University of London -- Endowments.; Copyright -- United States.; Censorship -- United States.; Free trade -- United States.; Publishers and publishing.; Authors and publishers.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States -- Foreign relations -- Great Britain.; Scrapbooks.;;; Putnam, George Palmer, 1814-1872.; Bryant, William Cullen, 1794-1878.; Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889.; Cleveland, Grover, 1837-1908.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1850-1924.; Lincoln, Robert Todd, 1843-1926.; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920.; Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919.; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1841-1935.; Root, Elihu, 1845-1937.; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946.; Jusserand, J. J. (Jean Jules), 1855-1932.; Foster, Gregory, Sir.; Taft, William H. (William Howard), 1857-1930.; Freeman, Edward Augustus, 1823-1892.; Olmsted, Frederick Law, 1870-1957.; Fuller, Anna, 1853-1916.; Bryce, James Bryce, Viscount, 1838-1922.
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Literature; Politics, Government, and Law; Politics and Politicians
Container List
- ADDRESSES: Presumably, these addresses were all given by Mr. Putnam. When "cards" are indicated, the speech is in outline, or brief-note form. When "mss," for manuscript, is indicated, the speech is in more complete form, and on regular sized paper: (Box 1)
  - ABRAHAM LINCOLN. Springfield, Illinois. Cards, 2-12-1927 (Box 1)
  - ABRAHAM LINCOLN. Republican Club, Waldorf. Mss., 2-12-1929 (Box 1)
  - ABRAHAM LINCOLN, THE GREAT CAPTAIN, Oxford. Mss., 5-7-1928 (Box 1)
  - ABRAHAM LINCOLN, THE GREAT CAPTAIN, MEMORIES OF A VETERAN. 3 copies, only one marked Springfield. Mss., 2-12-1927 (Box 1)
  - ADDRESS TO LIBRARIANS - THE PRODUCTION AND DISTRIBUTION OF BOOKS. Mss., 8-22-17 (Box 1)
  - THE ALUMNI DINNER OF THE NEW YORK UNIVERSITY. Mss., 2-18-? (Box 1)
  - AMERICA AND ENGLAND, THEIR RELATIONS IN THE PAST AND THEIR OBLIGATIONS TO EACH OTHER TODAY. Cards. (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN FREE TRADE LEAGUE. Boston. Cards, 5-22-17 (Box 1)
  - AMERICAN INSTITUTE. Cards, 3-21-? (Box 1)
  - THE AMERICAN LEAGUE TO ENFORCE PEACE. National Liberal Club. Mss., 5-30-? (Box 1)
  - ANDREW JACKSON. Cards. (Box 1)
  - ANGLO-AMERICAN RELATIONS. The British Schools and Universities Association. Mss., 5-24-1915 (Box 1)
  - ANTI-DISLOYALTY MASS MEETING. Cards, 11-2-1917 (Box 1)
  - ARMENIA. Columbia University. Cards, 3-30-1916 (Box 1)
  - ARTS CLUB. Cards, 11-11-? (Box 1)
  - THE ASSOCIATION OF ENGLISH SPEAKING PEOPLES. Cards. (Box 1)
  - THE ASSOCIATION OF THE HUDSON RIVER VALLEY. 2 copies. Cards and Mss. (Box 1)
  - AUTHOR'S CLUB. Cards, 2-14-1914 (Box 1)
  - AUTHORS' CLUB, WATCH NIGHT, THE OLYMPIAN HEIGHTS OF LITERATURE. Mss. (Box 1)
  - AUTHORS' CLUB. Cards, 12-31-1918 (Box 1)
  - BALDWIN MEMORIAL MEETING. Mss. (Box 1)
  - BALDWIN-NOTES FROM THE SPEECH. Mss. (Box 1)
  - BAYARD TAYLOR 1825-1925. West Chester, Pennsylvania. Mss., 1-10-1925 (Box 1)
  - BENJAMIN FRANKLIN. Free Thinkers Society of New York. Cards, 1-17-1925 (Box 1)
  - THE BEST SELLER. Authors' Club, Watch-Night. Cards, 1913 (Box 1)
  - BIRTHDAY DINNER. Cards, 4-2-1924 (Box 1)
  - THE BIRTHDAY OF HENRY (Henry Holt). Mss. (Box 1)
  - BOOKS AND THEIR MAKERS IN THE EARLY MIDDLE AGES. Mss. (Box 1)
  - BROWNING LITERARY SOCIETY. Philadelphia. Cards, 4-2-1925 (Box 1)
  - THE CALL OF THE REPUBLIC. Cornell University students. Mss., 5-8-1917 (Box 1)
  - THE CALL OF THE REPUBLIC. Address for teachers, Brooklyn. Cards, 3-12-1918 (Box 1)
  - CANADIAN CLUB. Cards, 12-14-1917 (Box 1)
  - CARL SCHURZ. Mss. (Box 1)
  - CAUSES OF THE CIVIL WAR. Cards. (Box 1)
  - CENSORSHIP. Cards, 8-29-1925 (Box 1)
  - CENTURY CLUB. Cards, 3-14-1927 (Box 1)
  - CENTURY CLUB. Mss. (Box 1)
  - CENTRAL HALL. Cards, 7-4-1918 (Box 1)
  - CENTRAL PARK. Cards, 2-5-? (Box 1)
  - CHARLES DICKENS AND RELATIONS BETWEEN ENGLAND AND AMERICA. Dickens Society. Cards, 2-7-1922 (Box 1)
  - CITATIONS FROM GERMAN WRITERS. Cards. (Box 1)
  - CITIZENSHIP. 2 copies, Cards and Mss., 1-12-? (Box 1)
  - CITY CLUB. RECORD OF ITS PURPOSE AND WORK, 1892-1925. Cards, 11-16-1925 (Box 1)
  - COBDEN CLUB. House of Commons. Cards, 6-2-1921 (Box 1)
  - COBDEN CLUB-REPORT ON FREE TRADE CONDITIONS IN AMERICA. Cards, 6-5-1923 (Box 1)
  - COLUMBIA HISTORY CLUB-EPISODES FROM THE WAR PERIOD 1861-1865. Cards, 3-19-1909 (Box 1)
  - COMMEMORATION OF THE SIGNING OF THE CONSTITUTION. Washington Irving High School. Cards, 9-17-1919 (Box 2)
  - COMMERCIAL MORALITY. College of Commerce. Mss., 3-10-1905 (Box 2)
  - CONFERENCE ON INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS. Cards, 6-19-1915 (Box 2)
  - THE CONSTITUTION. Sunrise Club. Cards, 4-5-1920 (Box 2)
  - THE CONSTITUTION, City College. Cards, 4-7-1921 (Box 2)
  - CONTEMPORARY CLUB. Philadelphia. 2 copies, Cards and Mss., 11-8-1915 (Box 2)
  - DECORATION DAY. Cards, 5-30-1919 (Box 2)
  - DARTMOUTH POLITY CLUB. The American Citizen, His Duties and His Rights. Cards, 10-13-1916 (Box 2)
  - DEFENSE. Discussion with Villard. Cards, 1915-1916 (Box 2)
  - THE DEFENSE OF THE REPUBLIC. Cards, 5-29-1906 (Box 2)
  - THE DEVELOPMENT OF OUR CITY. Cards. (Box 2)
  - THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE CONCEPTION OF IMMATERIAL PROPERTY. Mss. (Box 2)
  - THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE UNDERSTANDING ON THE PART OF MEN. Mss., 11-1897 (Box 2)
  - DINNER OF THE HUGHES ALLIANCE IN HONOR OF GOV. WILLIAM CAMERON FORMES. Mss., 10-20-1916 (Box 2)
  - DINNER OF THE NINETEENTH ARMY CORPS. Cards, 10-19-1914 (Box 2)
  - DINNER OF THE TENTH ARMY CORPS. Mss., 4-18-1911 (Box 2)
  - DINNER TO THE CONTRIBUTORS TO THE JAPAN VOLUME. Mss., 2-16-1915 (Box 2)
  - DINNER TO THE VETERANS OF 1861-1865. Cards, 3-20-1928 (Box 2)
  - DUBLIN, NEW HAMPSHIRE. Cards, 7-24-1920 (Box 2)
  - DUBLIN CLUB. The United States and the War of German Agression. Cards, 9-1-1917 (Box 2)
  - THE DUTIES AND THE RIGHTS OF AMERICAN CITIZENS. Cards, 11-14-1916 (Box 2)
  - E-S-U. London. Cards, 6-10-1924 (Box 2)
  - EARLY SETTLERS. Westchester Historical Society. Cards, 10-29-1928 (Box 2)
  - THE ECONOMIC POLICY AND TARIFF SYSTEM OF THE UNITED STATES. A Buisness Man's View. Mss. (Box 2)
  - ENGLAND AND AMERICA, THEIR RELATIONS IN THE PAST AND THEIR PRESENT OBLIGATIONS TO EACH OTHER. San Francisco. Mss., 8-2-1922 (Box 2)
  - ENGLAND IN WAR TIME. Cards, 9-17-1918 (Box 2)
  - ENGLAND OF TODAY. Cards, 1-18-1926 (Box 2)
  - EQUAL AND RESTRICTED SUFFRAGE. Argument before Committee of Pennsylvania State Legislation. Cards, 3-22-1912 (Box 2)
  - THE EVOLUTION OF THE BOOK. Columbia Graduate Association. 2 copies. Mss., 3-31-1905 (Box 2)
  - THE EVOLUTION OF THE BOOK. Arts, Club. Cards, 11-29-1916 (Box 2)
  - EVOLUTION OF PROPERTY IN LITERATURE. Author's Club, Boston. Cards, 12-1-1916 (Box 2)
  - EXPENDITURE. Cards. (Box 2)
  - EXPORT OF MUNITIONS. Cards. (Box 2)
  - FIRM DINNER. Cards, 4-2-1924 (Box 2)
  - THE FREE THINKERS OF AMERICA. Cards. (Box 2)
  - FREE TRADE LEAGUE. Liverpool. Mss., 6-24-1919 (Box 2)
  - FREEDOM OF TRADE. Sunrise Club. Cards, 12-14-1922 (Box 2)
  - FREE TRADE LIBERALS. Cards, 7-13-1925 (Box 2)
  - FRIENDS OF GERMAN DEMOCRACY. Cards. (Box 2)
  - FRIENDS OF WASHINGTON IRVING. 3 copies. Mss. (Box 2)
  - GEORGE WASHINGTON, IN COMMEMORATION, The Jumel House. Cards, 3-9-? (Box 2)
  - THE GERMAN IDEA OF PEACE TERMS. Cards. (Box 2)
  - GERMAN MISSIONARIES. Cards, 12-23-1914 (Box 2)
  - GLIMPSES OF ENGLAND. Cards, 8-28-1915 (Box 2)
  - GRANT. Cards. (Box 2)
  - GREETINGS TO THE FIRM OF MINTON AND BALCH. Cards, 1-21-1925 (Box 2)
  - GROLIER CLUB. Cards, 8(?)-18-1915 (Box 2)
  - GROVER CLEVELAND ASSOCIATION. Cards, 3-14-1927 (Box 2)
  - HEBER NEWTON. Mss. (Box 2)
  - HEAD MASTERS. Cards, 2-9-1918 (Box 2)
  - HENRY HOLT. Publishers Lunch Club. Cards, 3-4-1926 (Box 2)
  - HONOR TO A GREAT AMERICAN. Cards. (Box 2)
  - HOOVER MEETING. Cards, 7-19-1917 (Box 2)
  - IDEA OF PROSPERITY IN LITERATURE. Mss. (Box 2)
  - THE IDEALS OF AN EARLY VICTORIAN. Mss. (Box 2)
  - IN MEMORY OF GEORGE WHALE. Mss. (Box 2)
  - INAUGURATION OF BUILDING FOR THE USE IN THE MECHANICAL TRAINING OF THE BLIND. Mss., 10-19-1912 (Box 2)
  - INCIDENTS AND EPISODES OF THE YEARS OF THE CIVIL WAR. University Club. Cards, 1-26-1929 (Box 2)
  - INFLUENCE OF THE PRINTED WORD ON THE RELATIONS AMONG MEN THROUGHOUT THE WORLD. Mss. (Box 2)
  - INTERNATIONAL ARBITRATION AND CONCILIATION. Cards, 5-27-1916 (Box 2)
  - IRVING. Cards, 6-27-1927 (Box 2)
  - IRVING COMMEMORATION. Mss., 4-8-1914 (Box 2)
  - ISRAEL PUTNAM. To the Putnam Association. Mss. (Box 2)
  - ISRAEL PUTNAM. Mss., 9-19-1922 (Box 2)
  - ISRAEL PUTNAM, THE MAN. Cards, 8-11-1920 (Box 2)
  - ISRAEL AND RUFUS PUTNAM, Sons of the Revolution. Cards, 1-25-1926 (Box 2)
  - ISSUES OF THE CIVIL WAR. Lecture at Princeton. University. Cards, 4-13-1912 (Box 2)
  - JOSEPH FORCE NEWTON. 2 copies. Mss., 1-25-1920 (Box 2)
  - LEAGUE FOR POLITICAL EDUCATION. Episodes of the Civil War, or the Men Behind the Guns. Cards, 2-25-1923 (Box 2)
  - LEAGUE OF NATIONS. Cards. (Box 2)
  - THE LEAGUE TO ENFORCE PEACE. Cards. (Box 2)
  - LINCOLN. Pilgrim Hall, New York. Cards, 2-12-1917 (Box 2)
  - LINCOLN AND AMERICANISM. Cards, 11-7-1920 (Box 2)
  - LINCOLN AND THE AMERICAN CIVIL WAR. Oxford. Cards, 5-26-? (Box 2)
  - LINCOLN AND THE IDEALS OF THE REPUBLIC. Mss., 5-30-1929 (Box 2)
  - LINCOLN AND THE ISSUES OF THE WAR. Cards. (Box 3)
  - LITERARY PROPERTY. Mss., 10-1894 (Box 3)
  - THE LITERARY RELATIONS OF ENGLAND AND AMERICA. Cards, 7-5-1925 (Box 3)
  - THE LITERATURE OF THE WAR. Writers Club. Cards, 2-19-1918 (Box 3)
  - LOYAL LEGION. An Experience in Virgina Prisons. Cards, 12-7-1910 (Box 3)
  - LOYAL LEGION. Cards, 5-2-1917 (Box 3)
  - LUSITANIA. Carnegie Hall. Cards, 5-7-1916 (Box 3)
  - LUSITANIA MEMORIAL MEETING. Cards, 5-19-1916 (Box 3)
  - MADE FOR THE ORGANIZATION OF THE REPUBLICAN PARTY. Jackson, Michigan. Cards, 7-6-1954 (Box 3)
  - MAINE WOMAN'S CLUB. Waldorf-Astoria. Cards, 11-6-1920 (Box 3)
  - MAJOR PUTNAM'S REMARKS AT THE DINNER TO SIR WILLIAM BEVERIDGE. Mss., 5-5-1921 (Box 3)
  - MEMORIES, LITERARY AND OTHER OF OLD NEW YORK. Arts Club. Cards, 3-20-1916 (Box 3)
  - MEMORIES OF BAYARD TAYLOR. Cards, 1-10-1925 (Box 3)
  - MEMORIES OF AN OCTOGENARIAN. Cards, 8-25-1928 (Box 3)
  - MEMORIES OF OLD-TIME CENTURIANS. Cards, 3-10-1928 (Box 3)
  - MEMORIES OF WASHINGTON IRVING. Mss., 10-21-1924 (Box 3)
  - MONMOUTH COUNTY HISTORICAL ASSOCIATION. Cards, 8-26-1913 (Box 3)
  - NATIONAL DEFENSE. Cards, 4-15-1915 (Box 3)
  - NATIONAL DEFENSE. Security League. Cards, 6-15-1915 (Box 3)
  - NATIONAL INSTITUTE SOCIAL SCIENCES. Cards, 1-17-1918 (Box 3)
  - NATIONAL LIBERAL CLUB. A New Declaration of Independence. Cards, 7-4-1918 (Box 3)
  - NEW YORK OLD AND NEW. Town Hall. Cards, 4-7-1921 (Box 3)
  - NEW YORK PORT SOCIETY. Cards, 2-7-1918 (Box 3)
  - NEWARK REFORM CHURCH. Cards, 11-3-1920 (Box 3)
  - NINETEENTH ARMY CORPS AND DEPARTMENT OF THE SOUTH. Mss., 1-19-1917 (Box 3)
  - NOTES FOR LECTURE AT WILLIAMS COLLEGE. Mss., 3-3-1906 (Box 3)
  - NOTES FOR THE TALK ON LITERARY PROPERTY FOR THE SUNDAY EVENING CLUB. Mss., 2-18-1906 (Box 3)
  - NOTES FOR THE LIBRARIAN ASSOCIATION MEETING. Mss., 2-17-? (Box 3)
  - THE OLD SETTLERS ASSOCIATION. Cards, 3-18-1914 (Box 3)
  - OLDE SETTLERS. Cards, 1-17-1918 (Box 3)
  - OMAR KHAYYAM CLUB. Mss., 5-11-1905 (Box 3)
  - OMAR KHAYYAM CLUB. Cards, 6-24-1926 (Box 3)
  - PACIFISM. Cards. (Box 3)
  - PAINE MEMORIAL DINNER. Cards, 1-29-1910 (Box 3)
  - PEACE AND ARMAMENTS. Cards. (Box 3)
  - PEACE SOCIETY. Mss., 11-20-1909. (Box 3)
  - PRECIS OF AN ADDRESS OF G. H. PUTNAM. Mss. (Box 3)
  - PRESENTATION OF THE FLAG OF THE 176th REGIMENT NEW YORK VOLUNTEERS TO THE 7th REGIMENT NEW YORK SNG. Cards, 11-12-1915 (Box 3)
  - PROVIDENCE. Cards, 12-7-1918 (Box 3)
  - PUBLIC OPINION IN A DEMOCRACY. The Civic Forum of the Bronx. Cards, 12-3-1916 (Box 3)
  - PUBLISHERS LUNCH CLUB. Cards, 4-2-1924 (Box 3)
  - RATIONALIST PRESS DINNER. Cards, 5-27-1919 (Box 3)
  - RELATIONS OF AMERICA AND ENGLAND. Cards, 1-9-1922 (Box 3)
  - RELATIONS OF THE U.S. WITH THE ISSUES OF THE EUROPEAN WAR. Dartmouth College Graduate Club. Cards, 10-14-1916 (Box 3)
  - RESTRICTED SUFFERAGE. Cards. (Box 3)
  - RIGHTS OF AMERICAN CITIZENS. Carnegie Hall. Cards, 3-13-1916 (Box 3)
  - ROOSEVELTIANA. Cards. (Box 3)
  - SHAKESPEARE. Cards, 4-23-1924 (Box 3)
  - SLOVAK ALLIANCE. Cards, 2-15-1917 (Box 3)
  - SONS OF THE REVOLUTION. Mss., 1-25-1926 (Box 3)
  - SPHINX CLUB. Cards, 1-31-1919 (Box 3)
  - STATEMENT OF BRONSART VON SCHELLENDORP, MINISTER OF WAR FOR PRUSSIA. Cards. (Box 3)
  - STEPHEN LANGTON. Cards. (Box 3)
  - TALK ON CENSORSHIP. Mss., 2-22-? (Box 3)
  - THE U.S. IN ITS RELATIONS TO THE EUROPEAN WAR. Toronto. Cards, 11-10-1916 (Box 3)
  - UNIVERSITY FORUM. Mss., 1-19-1915 (Box 3)
  - THE WARNER SISTERS AND THE LITERARY INFLUENCE OF THE WRITERS OF THE HUDSON RIVER VALLEY. Cards. (Box 3)
  - WASHINGTON IRVING. 2 copies. Cards and Mss. (Box 3)
  - WASHINGTON IRVING SOCIETY OF WASHINGTON HEIGHTS. Mss., 7-22-1882 (Box 3)
  - WEST POINT. 2 copies. Cards and Mss. (Box 3)
  - WHY ENGLAND IS AT WAR. Mt. Morris Church. Cards, 2-21-1915 (Box 3)
  - THE WORLD COURT. Cards. (Box 3)
  - YE OLDE SETTLERS. Cards, 1-20-1916 (Box 3)
- ARTICLES:
  - AGRICULTURE THE PURSUIT FOR THE NATION. Handwritten., 3-12-1859. (Box 4)
  - AMERICA AND ENGLAND. Typed. (Box 4)
  - AMERICAN AND ENGLAND. Revised. 2 complete and 1 partial copy. All Typed. (Box 4)
  - AMERICAN AND ENGLAND - A DECLARATION OF INTERDEPENDENCE. Typed. 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - AMERICAN IDEALS. Partial copy, typed. (Box 4)
  - AMERICAN LITERATURE ARTICLE ON WASHINGTON IRVING. (Note, "Warner's Introduction to the Geoffrey Crayon Edition.") Typed. (Box 4)
  - AN ASSURED PEACE. Partial. (Note, "Free Trade Broadside.") Typed. (Box 4)
  - AUSTRALIA. (Note, "My First Composition, Geo. Haven Putnam, 1854.") Handwritten. (Box 4)
  - THE BATTLE OF THE FOOTBALL. Handwritten., 2-26-1859 (Box 4)
  - "A BOOK IS A BLESSED COMPANION…" Typed., 2-1913 (Box 4)
  - CENSORSHIP. Typed. (Box 4)
  - THE CENSORSHIP OF THE CHURCH AND ITS INFLUENCE ON THE PRODUCTION AND DISTRIBUTION OF LITERATURE. Typed. (Box 4)
  - CITATIONS FROM PERICLES' ORATIONS OVER THE DEAD IN ATHENS. Typed. (Box 4)
  - CIVIL EFFICIENCY. Typed., 2-24-1917 (Box 4)
  - THE COMPOSITION OF OUR SCHOOL. Handwritten., 2-4-1859 (Box 4)
  - A CRITICISM ON A STORY OF REAL LIFE. Handwritten., 1-14-1859 (Box 4)
  - THE DEATH OF LINCOLN. (Note, "Bernard School, Aug. 1925.") Typed., 8-1925 (Box 4)
  - DEBIT AND CREDIT. Handwritten., 1-19-1876 (Box 4)
  - A DECLARATION OF INTERDEPENDENCE. (Note, "For Symposium in 'Daily Mail' - 4th July 1918." Typed., 7-4-1918 (Box 4)
  - THE DEFENSE OF THE REPUBLIC. Typed. (Box 4)
  - THE DEFENSE OF THE REPUBLIC AND THE FULFILLMENT OF OUR NATIONAL OBLIGATIONS. Typed. (Box 4)
  - THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE CONCEPTION OF IMMATERIAL PROPERTY. Typed. 2 copies. (Box 4)
  - THE DEVELOPMENT OF THE CONCEPTION OF LITERARY PROPERTY. 2 partial copies. Typed. (Box 4)
  - THE DISADVANTAGES OF AMERICANS. Handwritten., 4-21-59 (Box 4)
  - THE EARLY PRINTERS OF THE LOW COUNTRIES. Typed notes., 10-1897 (Box 4)
  - THE ECONOMIC AND TARIFF SYSTEM OF THE UNITED STATES: A BUISNESS MAN'S VIEW. 2 copies, one marked 3-1928, Washington Conference. Typed. (Box 4)
  - ELECTRICAL PSYCHOLOGY. 2 parts. Handwritten. (Box 4)
  - ENGLISH-AMERICAN RELATIONS. Typed. (Box 4)
  - THE ENGLISH LANGUAGE AND WORLD PEACE. Typed. For Cosmos Newspaper Syndicate. (Box 4)
  - THE ENGLISH SPEAKING UNION AND THE LEAGUE OF NATIONS. Typed. (Box 4)
  - AN EPISODE OF THE CIVIL WAR. Typed, For Red Cross Magazine. (Box 4)
  - EQUAL SUFFRAGE. Typed. (Box 4)
  - EVENING POST ARTICLE ON LINCOLN. Typed. (Box 4)
  - EVOLUTION OF THE BOOK. Notes. Typed. (Box 4)
  - EXTRACTS FROM A VACATION RAMBLE. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - THE FATHER OF ZEBEDEE'S CHILDREN. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - THE FISCAL QUESTION IN THE UNITED STATES. Notes, Typed. (Box 5)
  - FISHKILL. Typed. 2 copies. (Box 5)
  - FIVE MINUTES. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - FRANKLIN DELANO ROOSEVELT. Typed. (Box 5)
  - FREEDOM OF TRADE VS. PROTECTION. AS A NATIONAL OR INTERNATIONAL POLICY. Typed. 2 copies. (Box 5)
  - GERMANY. 2 parts. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - HOME. Handwritten., 5-7-1859. (Box 5)
  - AN INCIDENT OF THE CIVIL WAR. Typed. (Box 5)
  - IS PROTECTION A SAFE BULWARK FOR THE NATION? Typed., 10-18-1918 (Box 5)
  - LINCOLN AND BRYANT. Typed. (Box 5)
  - LINCOLN AND THE ISSUES OF THE CIVIL WAR. Typed. (Box 5)
  - LINCOLN, THE GREAT CAPTAIN. Typed. (Box 5)
  - THE LITERARY RELATIONS OF ENGLAND AND AMERICA. (Note, "Original sent to Kansas City Star.") Typed. (Box 5)
  - LITERARY RELATIONS OF AMERICAN AND ENGLAND. Typed. (Box 5)
  - LITERATURE AND INTERNATIONAL RELATIONS. Typed. (Box 5)
  - LOYAL LEGION IN THE PHILIPPINES. (Note, "The Republic.") Typed., 2-9-1907 (Box 5)
  - MEDICAL JOURNAL AND RECORD. Typed. (Box 5)
  - MEMOIR OF MACHILLAN. (Note, "Notes for a Review.") Typed., 11-23-1910 (Box 5)
  - MEMORIES OF MY YOUTH 1844-1865. A Study by Dr. Ralcy Hasted Bell. Typed. (Box 5)
  - MEMORIES OF YOUTH - AN AFTERMATH. Typed. (Box 5)
  - THE MIZ AND THE MUZ. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - NAPOLEON BONAPARTE. Partial, Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - NEW YORK OLD AND NEW. 7 partial copies. Typed. (Box 5)
  - ON THE ART OF SAYING NO. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - ON SOME MURAL INSCRIPTIONS. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - OLD YORK. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - OUR CITY PARKS. Handwritten., 5-19-1859 (Box 5)
  - OUR PHILOSOPHER IN THE CITY. 2 parts. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - THE OTHER SIDE. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - POLITICS AS A BARRIER TO AN ADEQUATE AND EFFICIENT SYSTEM OF NATIONAL DEFENSE. (Note, "For the Annals of the Academy of Political Science.") Typed. (Box 5)
  - PROPERTY. DEFINITIONS OF. Typed. Notes. (Box 5)
  - PUBLISHERS' NOTE. Typed., 4-20-1921 (Box 5)
  - THE QUESTION OF NATIONAL DEFENSE. Typed. (Box 5)
  - SHAKESPEARE AND THE LITERARY RELATIONS OF ENGLAND AND AMERICA. Typed., 5-12-1917 (Box 5)
  - SUCCESS. Typed. (Box 5)
  - SUCCESS IN LIFE AND THE FACTORS THAT HELP TO SECURE IT. Typed., 1-9-1925 (Box 5)
  - A SUNDAY'S DREAM. 3 parts. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - SURDS, ABSURDS, AND BEES. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - TARIFF MAKING IN PRACTICE. Typed. (Box 5)
  - THAT GRIDDLE. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - THEODORE ROOSEVELT. Typed. 2 copies. (Box 5)
  - TRADE UNIONS. Notes. Typed. (Box 5)
  - A VACATION RAMBLE. Notes. 2 parts. Handwritten. (Box 5)
  - WASHINGTON IRVING. (Note, "Original sent to Harpers 3-11-25.") Typed., 3-11-1925 (Box 5)
  - WASTE. Handwritten., 2-6-1878 (Box 5)
  - 28 partial articles with no date or other means of identification. (Box 6)
- CORRESPONDENCE:
  - From London., 10-7-1840 (Box 7)
  - George P. Putnam to Mrs. Bishop., 1841 (Box 7)
  - Richard Grant White to George P. Putnam., 11-21-1851 (Box 7)
  - Bayard Taylor to ?, 5-31-1855 (Box 7)
  - Haven Putnam to Mother., 7-2-1859 (Box 7)
  - George P. Putnam to Charles King. President, Columbia College., 6-22-1860 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 3-20-1861 (Box 7)
  - G. Haven Putnam to Father., 6-5-1861 (Box 7)
  - GHP to ?, 8-3-1861 (Box 7)
  - GHP to Sister Minnie., 3-19-1862 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 3-20-1862 (Box 7)
  - I. T. Fulos to Putnam., 4-7-1862 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Sister Minnie., 7-19-1862 (Box 7)
  - C. F. Estee to George P. Putnam. 2 letters., 12-9-1862 (Box 7)
  - G. S. Boutwell to George P. Putnam., 12-20-1862 (Box 7)
  - I. Bright to G. F. Putnam., 2-27-1863 (Box 7)
  - Note, "Written by NGP", 6-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Bishop., 9-29-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father. Original and typed copy., 10-11-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 10-15-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 11-8-1863 (Box 7)
  - To Mother. (Partial), 11-15-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Minnie., 11-19-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father. Original and typed copy., 11-27-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 11-28-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother. Original and typed copy., 12-27-1863 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 1-26-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 1-29-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 3-27-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Minnie., 4-2-1864 (Box 7)
  - GHP to VHP., 4-7-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Minnie., 5-24-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Minnie., 10-16-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother and Father., 10-25-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father and Mother., 11-13-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 12-18-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father and Mother., 12-11-1864 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father and Mother., 1-1-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 1-2-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 2-4-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 2-4-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 2-19-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 2-24-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 2-26-1865 (Box 7)
  - Victoriana H. Putnam to Mary Caroline., 4-5-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Father., 4-7-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Sister., 4-18-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 4-30-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Aunty., 6-8-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Minnie., 11-2-1865 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Sister., 3-7-1866 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Sister., 4-8-1866 (Box 7)
  - J. G. Brown to G. P. Putnam., 4-12-1866 (Box 7)
  - T. T Rossiter to G. P. Putnam., 11-6-1867 (Box 7)
  - William Hart to G. P. Putnam., 12-5-1867 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 4-1868 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Sister., 3-28-1869 (Box 7)
  - William Cullen Bryant to George P. Putnam., 8-4-1869 (Box 7)
  - G. W. Curtis to G. P. Putnam., 8-30-1869 (Box 7)
  - Wilkie Collins to Messrs. G. P. Putnam and Son., 9-7-1869 (Box 7)
  - From the Evening Post., 9-29-1869 (Box 7)
  - Fr. Hyacinthe to G. P. Putnam and Son., 10-26-1869 (Box 7)
  - Hay to George P. Putnam and Sons., 6-9-1870 (Box 7)
  - Haven to Mother., 7-24-1870 (Box 7)
  - Oliver Wendell Holmes to G. P. Putnam., 8-4-1870 (Box 7)
  - Edwin Booth to G. P. Putnam., 6-4-1871 (Box 7)